{
  "LinkedIn/Git": [
    {"question":"Which setting determines what pager is used when Git pages output?","answer":"core.pager"},
    {"question":"What is the best way to characterize the git commit structure?","answer":"Data snapshot"},
    {"question":"What is the difference between Git and SVN?","answer":"SVN is a centralized system, while Git is a distributed system."},
    {"question":"What are untracked files?","answer":"files in the working directory that Git does not know about because they have not been staged or committed"},
    {"question":"How can you check your current git version?","answer":"git --version"},
    {"question":"What files is this .gitignore programmed to leave out? #.swift\nbuild/\n\n*.txt\n*.metadata","answer":"All files in the build directory, as well as files ending with .txt or .metadata"},
    {"question":"Your current project has several branches; master, beta, and push-notifications. You've just finished the notification feature in the push-notification branch, and you want to commit it to beta branch. How can you accomplish this?","answer":"Checkout the beta branch and run git merge push-notifications"},
    {"question":"What situation can occur when attempting to combine branches containing changes to the same piece of code?","answer":"merge conflict"},
    {"question":"What does the -p option add to the output of the git log command?","answer":"It adds patch output that shows the differences introduced in each commit."},
    {"question":"You have just completed rebasing your master branch and need to manually update the remote master, even though there is a merge conflict. How can you accomplish this?","answer":"git push --force-with-lease"},
    {"question":"How can you exclude untracked files within the working directory from a Git repository?","answer":"Add a pattern matching the files to the .gitignore file."},
    {"question":"Consider the following Git workflow: following options is correct ?","answer":"1. Master 2. Hotfix 3. Develop 4. Feature 5. Release"},
    {"question":"What change will the following command make to the staging area files? git rm --cached testfile.js","answer":"testfile.js will be removed from the staging area but its changes will still be tracked."},
    {"question":"How do you save a search that you use often using GitHub?","answer":"Click Save on the search results page."},
    {"question":"Explain the concept of \"Git blame\" and when it is used in a version control workflow.","answer":"Git blame is a tool for displaying who last modified each line of a file, helping to track changes and understand code history and authorship."},
    {"question":"What information does the git config file store?","answer":"local and global repository options"},
    {"question":"After accidentally deleting a branch in your local repository, how can you recover it?","answer":"Find the hash of the branch with the reflog command, then execute git checkout -b <branchname> <hash>"},
    {"question":"What command lets you create a connection between a local and remote repository?","answer":"git remote add origin"},
    {"question":"How can you display a list of files added or modified in a specific commit?","answer":"Use the diff-tree command with the commit hash."},
    {"question":"How does Git internally manage branches?","answer":"by creating a pointer to the most recent snapshot/commit for the branch"},
    {"question":"You’re creating an action for the GitHub Marketplace. Why is it important to create a release?","answer":"To package your software so that it can become available through the Github Marketplace"},
    {"question":"Where are files stored before they are committed to the local repository?","answer":"Staging area"},
    {"question":"What is GitHub?","answer":"A hosting platform for Git repositories"},
    {"question":"In GitHub Projects, how can you assign an issue to a collaborator?","answer":"Select their username from the Assignees field."},
    {"question":"After checking your git status you get the following output, which shows the file beta-notes.js in the commit but also unstaged. How can this situation occur? Change to be committed:\n\n(use \"git reset HEAD <file>...\" to unstage)\nmodified: beta-notes.js\nChanges not staged for commit:\n(use \"git add <file>...\" to update what will be committed)\n(use \"git checkout --<file>...\" to discard changes in working directory)\n\nmodified: beta-notes.js","answer":"beta-notes.js was staged, then modified afterwards, creating two different versions of the file"},
    {"question":"Describe what these Git commands do to the commit history:\ngit reset --hard HEAD~5\ngit merge --squash HEAD@{1}","answer":"The current branch's HEAD is reset back five commits, then prior commits are squashed into a single commit."},
    {"question":"What does the git stash drop command do?","answer":"removes the most recent stash entry"},
    {"question":"What is the difference between git branch -d and git branch -D?","answer":"-d deletes the local branch, while -D deletes the local branch regardless of push and merge status."},
    {"question":"What is the best way to report a bug to a GitHub project?","answer":"Search for the bug in the project's existing issues and create a new one if it hasn't been reported yet."},
    {"question":"How many ways are present in Git to integrate changes from one branch into another?","answer":"2"},
    {"question":"You want to perform a git reset but cannot recall all of the available options. What command would you use to see a description of them?","answer":"git help reset"},
    {"question":"After mistakenly staging a file named myFile to the index, how would you remove it from the index to exclude it from your next commit?","answer":"Use git reset myFile.txt."},
    {"question":"Assigning an issue to a person implies that they ____","answer":"are responsible for resolving the issue"},
    {"question":"How can you get better suggestions when creating functions?","answer":"Type “function” and then add a detailed and expressive function name."},
    {"question":"What feature does the shortcut /table activate when used inside a GitHub comment section?","answer":"A markdown table structure"},
    {"question":"What is the difference between using the git stash and git stash pop commands?","answer":"git stash creates a stash entry, while git stash pop places a saved state from the stash list onto the working directory"},
    {"question":"After pushing commits to the remote repository for the first time using the command below, what shorthand command can you use in future? git push -u origin master","answer":"git push"},
    {"question":"Which option enables inclusion of committer name in custom log format?","answer":"%cn"},
    {"question":"Which command would remove a file named wrongfile from the current branch of a repository, the index, and working files?","answer":"git rm wrongfile\ngit commit -m \"Removed file\""},
    {"question":"You’re reviewing a file in a repository and want to link to the current version of the file, even if it gets updated later. How can you achieve this?","answer":"Click Permalink on the code view"},
    {"question":"If you cloned an existing git repository, what would happen?","answer":"A copy of the repository would be created on your local machine"},
    {"question":"What is the fastest way to start a search using Github web pages?","answer":"Click the search box and type your searc query."},
    {"question":"While working on a feature branch you try to use \"git rerere\" to solve a recurring merge conflict but nothing is happening. What could be causing this issue?","answer":"\"rerere.enabled\" isn't enable in the config file."},
    {"question":"What does refs store?","answer":"Branch name"},
    {"question":"What practice can help reduce the chances of encountering a merge conflict?","answer":"Keep local repository branches in sync with upstream branches in the remote repository by committing,pushing and pulling frequently."},
    {"question":"What is the command to set the user email for the current repository?","answer":"git config user.email"},
    {"question":"How would you create a custom shortcut or command across your Git environment?","answer":"Create an alias using the git config command."},
    {"question":"What Git workflow is used by teams that collaborate on a single branch and avoid creating long-lived development branches?","answer":"Mainline flow"},
    {"question":"Looking at the following commands, describe what is happening.\ngit checkout feature-user-location\ngit cherry-pick kj2342134sdf090093f0sdgasdf99sdfo992mmmf9921231","answer":"The branch is switched to the feature-user-location branch, and the specified commit is applied to the branch."},
    {"question":"What happens if you run this command from your master branch?\ngit checkout -b beta-test","answer":"A new branch called beta-test will be created and switched to."},
    {"question":"After modifying some existing files in a repository, you decide to discard the changes. What command can you use?","answer":"git checkout"},
    {"question":"What option can you use to apply git configurations across your entire git environment?","answer":"--global"},
    {"question":"What is the main issue with using git rebase when working with multiple developers?","answer":"Rebase affects only your repository and creates a diff in the master branch."},
    {"question":"You stashed three sets of changes but cannot remember the contents of the first stash entry. What command would you use to see the details of the changes in the first of the three stash entries?","answer":"git stash show -p"},
    {"question":"After making a commit, you notice that you forgot to include changes to the doge.txt file. What command or commands would you use to add the changes to the commit?","answer":"git add doge.txt\n  git commit --amend --no-edit"},
    {"question":"What are two ways to help Copilot give you more accurate suggestions?","answer":"Add context in comments. & Use descriptive function names."},
    {"question":"You're looking at a repository page and click a folder name to open it. You have code search on, so you land in the code view. What is the quickest way to find a file on a path in your repo?","answer":"Press the slash(/) key and then the T key."},
    {"question":"Suppose you have created a bug fix on a new branch and want it to become part of the next production build generated from the main branch. What should you do next?","answer":"Create a pull request to merge your new branch into the main branch."},
    {"question":"What commands would you use to force an overwrite of your local files with the master branch?","answer":"git fetch --all\n  git reset --hard origin/master"},
    {"question":"How would you describe a forked repository?","answer":"a separate copy of a repository"},
    {"question":"When is the cherry-pick command used?","answer":"when a commit from one branch needs to be copied into another branch"},
    {"question":"Your company has moved its remote repository to GitHub at this location: https://github.com/yourcompany/core-api.git. What command updates the remote repository, named origin, to point to the new remote repository at this location?","answer":"git remote set-url origin https://github.com/yourcompany/core-api.git"},
    {"question":"Why would you use a pre-receive hook in your remote repository?","answer":"To execute a script when a remote receives a push that is triggered before any refs are updated"},
    {"question":"What features do repository managers such as GitHub provide beyond Git?","answer":"Repository managers provide an online service for hosting Git repositories that include collaboration features such as pull requests, issue tracking, and peer reviews."},
    {"question":"You are working on a project that uses a Python library and you want to find an example of how to use a function across all public repositories. Which part of GitHub’s platform would you use?","answer":"Search"},
    {"question":"Which use case is NOT a good candidate for a Git hook?","answer":"state dependent environment changes"},
    {"question":"What would happen if you ran the git reset testfile.js command?","answer":"testfile.js would be reverted to its last saved copy."},
    {"question":"_ will rewind your project to a specific point in time, losing all commits that came after it. _ will keep changes in those rewound commits as local modifications","answer":"git reset --hard; git reset --soft"},
    {"question":"What command would let you modify your previous commit?","answer":"--amend"},
    {"question":"Working late on a project, you need to find an issue that was assigned to you. What query do you type?","answer":"Is:issue assignee:username"},
    {"question":"Which command correctly creates a lightweight tag?","answer":"git tag v3.8.1"},
    {"question":"After starting to merge a feature branch into your master branch, you encounter a merge conflict and decide you do not want to perform the merge. How can you stop the merge and restore to the pre-merge state?","answer":"Use git merge --abort."},
    {"question":"After you've successfully merged two branches and committed the changes, what is the next step in keeping your git structure organized?","answer":"Run git branch -d <branch name> to delete the merged branch."},
    {"question":"While pushing changes to a remote repository, you receive the following message. How do you resolve this issue?","answer":"Execute a pull, then resolve any merge conflicts and execute another push."},
    {"question":"What statement best describes Git's concept of HEAD?","answer":"a pointer to the most recent commit in the currently checked-out branch"},
    {"question":"What command takes changes from the master branch on the remote repository origin and merges then to the local checked-out branch?","answer":"git pull origin master"},
    {"question":"Which option enables inclusion of author name in custom log format?","answer":"%an"},
    {"question":"What does commit object contain?","answer":"Reference to parent commit objects and a set of files, representing the state of a project at a given point of time, and an SHA1 name, a 40-character string that uniquely identifies the commit object."},
    {"question":" While modifying a file, you're unexpectedly assigned an urgent bug fix on another branch. How can you temporarily save your local work without committing?","answer":"Use git stash to save your work and come back later and reapply the stashed commit."},
    {"question":"After making some major changes to your code, you are a little nervous about committing. What command would you use to review the commit prior to making it?","answer":"git commit --dry-run"},
    {"question":"Which of the following is true of the git push command?","answer":"By default a push doesn't send tags to the remote repository."},
    {"question":"Why should you include a descriptive function name when writing code with Copilot?","answer":"It helps Copilot have better context for code assistance and generation."},
    {"question":"After a recent release with a stack trace, an issue is create that indicates the problem is with a newly added configuration property named MaxConnections. What command can find all commits that add or remove the string MaxConnections?","answer":"git log -S \"MaxConnections\""},
    {"question":"What is the operation doing given the Git commands below? git bisect start\ngit bisect bad 5d41402abc4b2a76b9719d911017c592\ngit bisect good 69faab6268350295550de7d587bc323d","answer":"It performs a binary search using a known bad commit and known good commit to determine which commit introduced a bug"},
    {"question":"What command finds the HEAD of the current branch?","answer":"git show-ref --head"},
    {"question":"How does Git think of its data?","answer":"Snapshot"},
    {"question":"Which key press returns a set of suggestions to pick from, when writing a Git command?","answer":"Tab"},
    {"question":"Git Pull is a combination of?","answer":"fetch and merge."},
    {"question":"How would you configure Git to abort a commit if a smoke test script fails?","answer":"Create a pre-commit hook to trigger the script."},
    {"question":"What is the difference between a soft reset (git reset --soft) and a hard reset (git reset –hard) ?","answer":"A soft reset only changes the commit that HEAD points to, while a hard reset resets the index and working tree to match the specified commit, discarding any changes."},
    {"question":"You are working on an AI app and need to add information on project tables about the AI model being targeted. What feature allows you to do this?","answer":"Custom fields"},
    {"question":"After staging a series of changes to the index, which command could you use to review them prior to a commit?","answer":"git diff --cached"},
    {"question":"Which of the following is called dumb protocol?","answer":"HTTP"},
    {"question":"What is the difference between initializing a normal repo and a bare repo?","answer":"Bare repos do not come with working or checked-out source files."},
    {"question":"You’re in the repo for a specific project while working on an app module. You want to look for some of the docs you’ve been working on, which you wrote in markdown. To quickly look in your own repo for all files with a markdown extension, press the slash (/) button on the keyboard while on the repository page and type ___.","answer":"Code:*.md"},
    {"question":"How would you delete a remote branch in your repository?","answer":"Use git push <remote_name> --delete <branch_name>"},
    {"question":"What conflicts can occur when forcing a push after rebasing?","answer":"The remote master branch could have existing changes overwritten."},
    {"question":"What type of Git hook could be used to validate that a commit message contains a ticket number?","answer":"commit-msg"},
    {"question":"What is a remote repository?","answer":"a version of the repository hosted on the internet or network that is pushed to or pulled from by collaborators"},
    {"question":"What is the default setting of git reflog when no subcommands are specified?","answer":"show"},
    {"question":"What command would you use to create a new git repository?","answer":"git init"},
    {"question":"You're creating an action for the Github marketplace. why is it importance to create a release?","answer":"to alow you to create .zip files that you can easily share & to package your software so that it can become available through the Github marketplace"},
    {"question":"Which user should be created first during setting up of SSH?","answer":"None of these"},
    {"question":"What command displays the difference between the working tree and the stage/index area, as well as files not tracked by Git?","answer":"git status"},
    {"question":"How could you squash multiple commits together without using git merge --squash?","answer":"Rebasing"},
    {"question":"What information do Git reflogs (reference logs) store?","answer":"updates to branch tips and other references in the local repository"},
    {"question":"What command would you use to stage changes to the index strictly for properties files in the current directory?","answer":"git add *.properties"},
    {"question":"How would you display a histogram showing inserts, deletion, and modifications per file for a specific commit along with its general commit information?","answer":"Use git show <commit> --stat"},
    {"question":"Which version onwards did Git offer reversing a file back to what it looked like when last committed?","answer":"1.6"},
    {"question":"You find a bug in your project, but can't locate where it was introduced in the commit history. How would you diagnose this problem?","answer":"Use git bisect to compare the buggy commit to an early commit that works as expected."},
    {"question":"You would like to restore some previously stashed work to a new branch. How can you do that?","answer":"Run git stash branch <branch name>"},
    {"question":"Which command will list tags with the 1.4.2 series?","answer":"git tag -l 'v1.4.2.*'"},
    {"question":"You have changed your mind about adding broccoli to your project. How should you remove it?","answer":"git clean -f"},
    {"question":"Which of the following is an integration manager?","answer":"Depends upon project type"},
    {"question":"Which Git command begins tracking of a new file?","answer":"add"},
    {"question":"Which of these terms best describes Git?","answer":"Distributed Version Control System"},
    {"question":"What is the purpose of C++ move constructor, and when is it automatically generated?","answer":"A move constructor allows efficient transfer of resources from one object to another,reducing unnecessary copying."},
    {"question":"Which command can be used to list the branches that have been merged into the currently checked-out branch?","answer":"git branch --merged"},
    {"question":"You’re organizing a desktop application project. You want to use an overview f your project statuses and be able to drag and drop issues. Which view would you use?","answer":"Board"},
    {"question":"Which option on the git log command allows you to limit output to commits made after certain date?","answer":"--since"},
    {"question":"Which strategy is used by Git for merging two branches?","answer":"octopus"},
    {"question":"What is version control?","answer":"a system that shows, tracks, and controls changes to a set of files over time"},
    {"question":"What does the following command do to the git repository?\ngit reset --soft HEAD^","answer":"It sets HEAD to the previous commit and leaves changes from the undone commit in the stage/index."},
    {"question":" Your team lead needs a list of all commits that will be moved before you perform a rebase. Which command can you use to access that information?","answer":"git rebase -i"},
    {"question":"While doing a code review, you want to start an issue by highlighting a function that takes up several lines of code. What is the fastest way to do this in code view?","answer":"Click the line number with the function and select reference function in an issue"},
    {"question":"What is the main purpose of the Chat panel?","answer":"To have a conversational discussion with the AI behind Copilot"},
    {"question":"What command creates a new branch from the currently checked-out branch?","answer":"git checkout -b <nameOfBranch>"},
    {"question":"What does a Template repository do?","answer":"It allows you to create a default structure and files based on the current repository."},
    {"question":"What is usually the extension of file which has the public key?","answer":"pub"},
    {"question":"Why would the following command be used? git rebase -i HEAD~10","answer":"To list the last 10 commits and modify them with either the squash or fixup command"},
    {"question":"How does the -p option change the behavior of the git add command","answer":"It allows developers to interactively choose which changes to tracked files are staged and outputs the differences for review."},
    {"question":"What command can you use to remove untracked files from the working directory?","answer":"git clean -d -f"},
    {"question":"After you make changes to a local repository, you run the following command. What will this do? git commit -a -m \"Refactor code base\"","answer":"Adds all modified files to the staging area, then commits them with a message"},
    {"question":"In a situation where you have several commits for a single task, what is the most efficient way to restructure your commit history?","answer":"Squash the related commits together into a single coherent commit."},
    {"question":"What is the difference between git fetch and git pull","answer":"git fetch updates remote tracking branches with changes from a remote repository, while git pull updates remote tracking branches with changes from a remote repository and merges them into their corresponding local branches."},
    {"question":"What is the staging area or index?","answer":"an area that stores information about changes that will be included in the next commit"},
    {"question":"Which of these is not a label that github creates by default?","answer":"repo"},
    {"question":"What command creates a near-exact copy of the entire repository from a server?","answer":"git clone <url>"},
    {"question":"After checking out a specific commit, you receive a warning message indicating You are in 'detached HEAD' state. What is Git warning you of?","answer":"The commit does not have a parent."},
    {"question":"When Git workflows contain a topic branch, what purpose does the topic branch serve?","answer":"Topic branches are short-lived branches used to store work related to a particular feature."},
    {"question":"What will the following command print to the Terminal?\ngit remote -v","answer":"A list of remote repositories and their URLs"},
    {"question":"After staging changes to several files, you realize the changes to the config.properties file are incorrect, and need to be removed from the stage and working directory. What command can you use to remove the staged changes to the file?","answer":"git reset HEAD^ -- config.properties"},
    {"question":"What does the RUN command do in a Dockerfile?","answer":"It allows you to execute a shell command during the image generation process"},
    {"question":"This command is an example of what kind of tag? git tag -a v1.4 -m \"ABCD v1.5\"","answer":"annotated"},
    {"question":"What is the difference between git stash pop and git stash apply?","answer":"git stash pop applies the topmost entry in the stash to the working files and removes it from the stash, while git stash apply applies the topmost entry in the stash to the working files but leaves it in the stash."},
    {"question":" You find that your project has a tag and branch both named push-notifications, which causes confusion when trying to print out given reference. How can you specify which branch you want to look at?","answer":"use git show refs/head/push-notifications"},
    {"question":"What Language is used in GIT?","answer":"C"},
    {"question":"How many individual commits can a single repository have?","answer":"any number of commits"},
    {"question":"What types of tags does Git support?","answer":"lightweight and annotated"},
    {"question":"When Git Workflows contain a long-running branch, what purpose does the long-running branch serve?","answer":"Long-running branches correspond to different stages of development and are always open for topic/feature branches to be pulled into."},
    {"question":"Which of the following is true when you use the following command?\ngit add -A","answer":"All new and updated files are staged"},
    {"question":"How would you delete unreachable objects older than a specified time from your project database?","answer":"git prune --expire <time>"},
    {"question":"What is the status of the beta-notes.js file in the following output? Changes not staged for commit:\n(use \"git add <file>...\" to update what will be committed)\n(use \"git checkout -- <file>...\" to discard changes in working directory)\n\nmodified: beta-notes.js","answer":"beta-notes.js is a tracked file and has been modified, but has not been added to the current commit."}
  ],
  "LinkedIn/Agile": [
    {"question":"Which statement is true about the actor in a user story?","answer":"The actor can be the system itself."},
    {"question":"What Agile practice best supports this principle: \"At regular intervals, the team reflects on how to become more effective, then tunes and adjusts its behavior accordingly\"?","answer":"Sprint Retrospective"},
    {"question":"In Large-Scale Scrum, what is the recommended ratio of Scrum Masters to teams?","answer":"One Scrum Master can support one to three teams."},
    {"question":"Which of the following elements is not a pillar of Scrum?","answer":"sustainability"},
    {"question":"In the Cynefin framework, where are \"best practices\" most appropriate?","answer":"In the Obvious regime"},
    {"question":"What is Open Space?","answer":"a meeting format where participants create and manage the agenda"},
    {"question":"What types of environments work best for Agile principles?","answer":"It works great in dynamic environments."},
    {"question":"You have noticed a pattern that the most interesting stories on the Sprint Backlog get started right away, and the least interesting stories languish or don't get done. What should you do?","answer":"Ask the Tech Lead to assign every story to a developer so they all get done efficiently and with accountability."},
    {"question":"Which is NOT a principle of the Scaled Agile Framework?","answer":"Centralize decision-making"},
    {"question":"What is the definition of capacity?","answer":"It is the maximum number of stories that will be allowed in a sprint."},
    {"question":"What is the expected outcome of the daily stand-up meeting?","answer":"team alignment on its plan for the day"},
    {"question":"Which choice is not a recognized framework for scaling Agile?","answer":"DUN"},
    {"question":"You are the Scrum Master and, having just facilitated a meeting, you're reflecting on ways to improve. What skill are you displaying?","answer":"being self-aware"},
    {"question":"Which task is not the product owner's responsibility?","answer":"giving feedback to developers about the user stories"},
    {"question":"What is the name of the information radiator that has multiple columns used to visualize the flow of work?","answer":"Kanban Board"},
    {"question":"What does collective ownership mean?","answer":"The team shares equally in the profits that the product generates."},
    {"question":"Who is responsible for a Scrum team's performance?","answer":"the Scrum Master"},
    {"question":"Why should you apply for the Weighted Shortest Job First?","answer":"to determine the economic sequencing of the backlog"},
    {"question":"What is a Scrum of Scrums?","answer":"It is a technique for two or more teams working together to coordinate their efforts."},
    {"question":"What does the Definition of Done mean?","answer":"The team has agreed on the criteria for story completion."},
    {"question":"Which statement concerning small, frequent releases of software is true?","answer":"It typically requires a high degree of automation."},
    {"question":"The Scaled Agile Framework advocates that, if you measure only one thing, what should you measure?","answer":"cost of delay"},
    {"question":"Which choice is _not_ considered during Sprint Planning?","answer":"stories that meet the Definition of Done"},
    {"question":"In the INVEST acronym for user stories, what does the \"V\" stand for?","answer":"valuable"},
    {"question":"What does EBM consider in Managerial Decisions?","answer":"Circumstance and ethical concerns"},
    {"question":"Which statement about estimating is not true?","answer":"Absolute estimating is more reliable than relative estimating."},
    {"question":"As an Agile coach, what should be your attitude toward your team members' individual goals and motivations?","answer":"Leverage them — use personal goals to encourage team members to raise their performance levels."},
    {"question":"Which statement about the Agile Manifesto is true?","answer":"It has been translated into dozens of languages and used around the world."},
    {"question":"What is the activity of clarifying and expanding user stories called?","answer":"backlog refinement"},
    {"question":"Which choice is not a benefit generally associated with product demonstrations?","answer":"Learn about feature estimates."},
    {"question":"In the Scaled Agile Framework, consecutive iterations are grouped into a PI. What is a PI?","answer":"Program Increment"},
    {"question":"What is a lean canvas?","answer":"It is a template for lightweight business plans that makes your assumptions explicit"},
    {"question":"Which scale is typically used for Planning Poker?","answer":"1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 8, 13, 20"},
    {"question":"Stacey's process complexity model shows us that agile thinking is best **___**.","answer":"Regardless of complexity or certainty"},
    {"question":"How can you improve interaction between team members?","answer":"Move people's workstations around in the team room to create new social possibilities"},
    {"question":"Product development organizations sometimes use descriptions of archetypal users and their values so that developers can design the system to meet their needs and wants. What are these descriptions called?","answer":"personas"},
    {"question":"People with a fixed mindset _ .","answer":"have better focus and longer attention spans"},
    {"question":"Which of the following statements about a Kanban control chart is false?","answer":"The control chart works best when the tasks that you're tracking are of different sizes."},
    {"question":"What is the term for a team member who is \"T-shaped\"?","answer":"generalizing specialist"},
    {"question":"What do you call the practice of writing a test before the code is written?","answer":"test-driven development"},
    {"question":"The team's manager wants to attend the Sprint Retrospective. What should you do?","answer":"Propose a different forum for the manager to meet with the team."},
    {"question":"What is the expected outcome of the Daily Scrum meeting?","answer":"team alignment on its plan for the day"},
    {"question":"What is not a technique used for splitting user stories?","answer":"split compound user stories"},
    {"question":"The team is not going to complete its Sprint Commitment. As a Team Facilitator, what should you do?","answer":"advise the PO as soon as possible"},
    {"question":"The VP of Engineering wants to start giving out a \"Team Member of the Sprint\" award to recognize a top performer in each group. What advice should you give this VP?","answer":"This is unhelpful because it can destroy the team unity essential to achieving high performance."},
    {"question":"Which outcome is not expected of a Sprint Review?","answer":"The team reflects on how to improve its performance."},
    {"question":"What is an Empathy Map?","answer":"It is a collaborative tool used to gain deeper insights into customers."},
    {"question":"Which statement is true about Agile?","answer":"Agile requires a high degree of discipline."},
    {"question":"Which ceremony should the Product Owner not attend?","answer":"code reviews"},
    {"question":"In Scrum, at the end of each sprint, there is a _ meeting in which the team receives and gives feedback on their processes and their performance.","answer":"retrospective"},
    {"question":"Which action is something the Team facilitator should NOT do?","answer":"Estimate story points."},
    {"question":"Which statement about the Agile Manifesto is true?","answer":"It was written in response to documentation-heavy software development project practices."},
    {"question":"What is the difference between a team's task board and a Kanban?","answer":"A Kanban has an explicit rule to limit WIP."},
    {"question":"When is the best time to review the team's burndown chart?","answer":"before the Sprint Retrospective"},
    {"question":"To whom should the Product Owner report?","answer":"the Product Manager"},
    {"question":"Which phrase best describes an Agile team?","answer":"A cross-functional, self-organized team with collective accountability."},
    {"question":"Which choice best describes an Agile Release Train (ART)?","answer":"continuous delivery"},
    {"question":"Which statement is not true about the product backlog?","answer":"It is a list of work items that are behind schedule."},
    {"question":"The Product Owner is focused on testing a new system concept in the marketplace as quickly and inexpensively as possible. What is this first-generation product called?","answer":"minimum viable product"},
    {"question":"In the Scaled Agile Framework, what is the role of Enablers?","answer":"They help extend the Architectural Runway."},
    {"question":"Which choice is not an expected benefit of refactoring?","answer":"Refactoring is used to fix bugs"},
    {"question":"What is the forming-storming-norming, performing model of team development known as?","answer":"the Tuckman model"},
    {"question":"What does being a Cross-Functional team mean?","answer":"That all the skills necessary exist within the team"},
    {"question":"What is the expected output of a Planning Poker meeting?","answer":"The stories were discussed and each had a story point estimate assigned."},
    {"question":"Which work descriptions are not written in the language of users?","answer":"tasks"},
    {"question":"Which statement about the actor in a user story can be true?","answer":"The actor can be the system itself"},
    {"question":"A team member has been showing signs of great personal distress: crying at work, snapping at colleagues, and having heated phone conversations. As a Team Facilitator, what should you do?","answer":"Advise the PO as soon as possible. (Old answer: Notify the team member's manager of your observations and ask the manager for help.)"},
    {"question":"What is the term for a team member who is \"T-skilled\"?","answer":"cross-functional"},
    {"question":"What is the Product Owner's role in deciding the priority of work in the sprint backlog?","answer":"None—the developers should prioritize the work in the sprint backlog."},
    {"question":"Having a mindset focused on growth and opportunity is healthy for Agile team members. How can you display a growth mindset?","answer":"See challenges as opportunities"},
    {"question":"Which statement best describes Agile, Lean, and Six Sigma?","answer":"They are strategies for delivering customer value."},
    {"question":"What is the name of the technique in which a story is broken down, input splits the data, and it results in a new output?","answer":"input-output processing"},
    {"question":"According to the Agile Manifesto, how often should developers and business people work together?","answer":"daily"},
    {"question":"Which statement describes Shu Ha Ri?","answer":"It is a model for skill development and mastery."},
    {"question":"According to the Agile Manifesto, your highest priority is to _.","answer":"satisfy the customer"},
    {"question":"What aspects of the product is the Product Owner responsible for?","answer":"All of the choices are correct"},
    {"question":"What is the Scrum Master's role during the daily stand-up?","answer":"Stand outside the circle of developers and listen for impediments."},
    {"question":"What is the definition of velocity?","answer":"The number of story points delivered during a sprint"},
    {"question":"Which choice is a pillar of Lean?","answer":"Respect for people and culture"},
    {"question":"Which of these traits is most important for being an effective Team Facilitator?","answer":"being self-aware"},
    {"question":"What is the name of the technique that divides a story into smaller pieces?","answer":"story slicing"},
    {"question":"What is the main benefit of a working agreement?","answer":"It defines the culture that the team aspires to achieve."},
    {"question":"What is the name for the practice of going to see a process in use at the point of value delivery?","answer":"Gemba Walk"},
    {"question":"In Agile, which of the following options is a high priority?","answer":"Working software"},
    {"question":"Which Jira feature provides an overview of multiple projects?","answer":"roll-up boards"},
    {"question":"What is the Product Owner's role regarding the product backlog?","answer":"The PO must identify the dependencies that impact the backlog."},
    {"question":"Which choice best describes the Team Facilitator?","answer":"an Agile coach"},
    {"question":"When planning a meeting, which action is most important?","answer":"clarifying the expected outcome"},
    {"question":"What is a PBI?","answer":"Product Backlog Item"},
    {"question":"As a Scrum Master, you have noticed a pattern that the most interesting stories on the sprint backlog get started right away, and the least interesting stories languish or don't get done. What should you do?","answer":"Share your observation with the team and invite them to own and solve the problem."},
    {"question":"What background information is most important for a successful Product Owner to understand?","answer":"The business context for the product."},
    {"question":"What is most important for a successful Product Owner to understand?","answer":"The business context for the product."},
    {"question":"What is an information radiator?","answer":"the task board"},
    {"question":"What does the Agile Manifesto indicate?","answer":"Responding to change is more valuable than following a plan."},
    {"question":"Which element is most important when describing your product?","answer":"its benefits"},
    {"question":"Where are teams most likely to find the first signs of potential problems?","answer":"Daily Scrums"},
    {"question":"Which of the following scrum events is dedicated to process improvement?","answer":"The sprint retrospective"},
    {"question":"How can you improve interaction between team members?","answer":"Move people's workstations around in the team room to create new social possibilities."},
    {"question":"You are facilitating a meeting and, unexpectedly, a key person doesn't attend. What should you do?","answer":"Ask all meeting participants what they want to do about the one person's absence"},
    {"question":"As the Scrum Master, you've observed that team members are more comfortable communicating via instant messaging than through direct conversions. How can you encourage conversation between team members?","answer":"Since no one has come to you with a complaint, assume that the limited conversation works for everyone."},
    {"question":"What is Lean Canvas?","answer":"It is used to decompose the solution into epics, features, and stories"},
    {"question":"When working with a Scrum team, who is chiefly responsible for ensuring that the project delivers value?","answer":"Development Team"},
    {"question":"A team member comes to you with a complaint about another team member. What should you do?","answer":"Invite both people to a meeting and try to mediate the conflict."},
    {"question":"What is the name of the ceremony in which you inspect the work completed during the sprint?","answer":"Sprint Review"},
    {"question":"For a month-long sprint, the time-box for a sprint retrospective is _.","answer":"3 hours"},
    {"question":"The Product Owner complains to you that the team is not working hard enough and they need to increase their velocity by at least 50%. Which action should you not take?","answer":"Share the feedback from the PO and challenge the team to increase their velocity."},
    {"question":"Who decides what the team will work on?","answer":"a self-organizing team"},
    {"question":"Why should a team do refactoring?","answer":"It improves the design, which can lead to improved development efficiency and maintainability."},
    {"question":"You have classified the features in your backlog according to risk and value. Which features should the development team work on first?","answer":"high-value and high-risk"},
    {"question":"Which technique does not help prioritize the backlog?","answer":"Kaizen"},
    {"question":"Which statement about technical debt is true?","answer":"Adding technical debt should be avoided at all costs."},
    {"question":"Progress toward a sprint goal is in jeopardy because you have not received sales data. What should you do?","answer":"Share the problem with your team to see if they can create a solution"},
    {"question":"The team has an incomplete story at the end of the sprint and wants to claim partial credit for the work completed. What should you do?","answer":"Ask the product owner to revise the acceptance criteria so it can be accepted and counted"},
    {"question":"The team is not going to complete its Sprint Commitment. As the Team Facilitator, what should you do?","answer":"Point out the reasons why and collaborate on solutions."},
    {"question":"Which strategy is preferred for development teams?","answer":"Maximize outcome while minimizing output."},
    {"question":"Teams may encounter the need for \"technical\" user stories. Who decides the priority of these?","answer":"the Product Owner with help from the Tech Lead"},
    {"question":"Which choice is not a Scrum value?","answer":"integrity"},
    {"question":"There are several configurations of the Scaled Agile Framework in Version 5.0. Which is not one of the configurations?","answer":"SAFe Popular"},
    {"question":"Which is the best definition of story points?","answer":"They are a relative measure of the effort needed to complete a story."},
    {"question":"You are facilitating a meeting to decompose user stories and, unexpectedly, a development team member cannot attend. What should you do?","answer":"Ask all meeting participants what they want to do about the one person's absence"},
    {"question":"What happens in Sprint 0?","answer":"The team prepares to work on the product backlog."},
    {"question":"A team needs to do research, design, or prototyping. What is this type of story called?","answer":"Exploratory spike"},
    {"question":"What is the name of the practice in which a cross-functional team collaborates intensively to develop a new product idea?","answer":"Hackathon"},
    {"question":"What should happen if the Product Owner does not accept a story by the end of the iteration?","answer":"The story should be shown to stakeholders for their feedback."},
    {"question":"Which statement about burndown and burnup charts is not true?","answer":"Burndown charts are more useful than burnup charts."},
    {"question":"Which statement describes the flow of work in the Scaled Agile Framework?","answer":"It is neither \"push\" nor \"pull.\""},
    {"question":"What does the Definition of Ready mean?","answer":"The story is ready to be brought into a sprint."},
    {"question":"What is a DEEP product backlog?","answer":"Detailed Appropriately, Emergent, Estimated & Prioritized"},
    {"question":"The team is complaining that they send requests for clarification to the Product Owner, but these requests go unanswered. What action should you take?","answer":"Schedule a problem-solving session with the Product Owner and the other team members."},
    {"question":"When is the best time to update the team's burndown chart?","answer":"before the daily Scrum"},
    {"question":"When the team needs to make a decision, what is the best course of action?","answer":"Try to achieve consensus."},
    {"question":"Which type of Kanban diagram shows the number of issues in each of the states?","answer":"cumulative flow"},
    {"question":"When a user story is further decomposed, what are the elements called?","answer":"Who, What, Why"},
    {"question":"A manager informs you that a developer from another team is between assignments, and she wants to place the developer on your team for a few sprints. What should you do?","answer":"Explain to the manager that this will be disruptive to the team and ask that another assignment be found."},
    {"question":"The team complains that \"things have been falling through the cracks lately.\" What should you do?","answer":"Conduct a workshop to identify all of the things that need to be done and see who can help with each."},
    {"question":"On what are personas typically based?","answer":"real people, archetypal users, or composites of multiple users"},
    {"question":"Which factor should not be considered during Sprint Planning?","answer":"the number of stories in the product backlog"},
    {"question":"Which statement is not true about pair programming?","answer":"It has been discredited because it is too expensive."},
    {"question":"What is a user story?","answer":"The Agile term for a requirement"},
    {"question":"A project has some major risks that the team wants to mitigate. What is the best way to monitor how well this effort is going?","answer":"risk burndown graph"}
  ]
}
